ARUGA YUDISH FIRMANSYAH

081220151337 | Ayudish7@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/arugayudishf | https://github.com/ArugaYudish

Kota Bandung, Jawa Barat, 40151

I am an information systems student who can work together and work hard. Have an interest in IT and Business, I have experience as front end developer, coding teacher, systems analyst, and practical assistant for database programming courses. During college, I focused on self-development in coding, programming, databases, software design, business, and management.

Work Experiences

Ruang Guru - Indonesia

Sep 2022 - Present

Coding Teacher

- Explained more than 20 Projects to create simple games using scratch programming.
- Collaborated with each student to solve more than 30 problems in creating a game application using scratch.
- Evaluate and develop more than 10 student-made games.

HashMicro - Jakarta, Indonesia

Feb 2022 - Dec 2022

System Analyst

- Create and design more than 20 features for companies and clients and apply these designs to get the desired system and get client satisfaction.
- Perform analysis and testing of 50+ system flows in the company so as to get quality system results.
- Collaborated and communicate 30+ client wishes to the IT division and enterprise developers.

Sinergi Merah Putih - Indonesia

Jun 2022 - Nov 2022

Front End Developer

- Design and build a mini project website using Nuxt JS with more than 10 features.
- Analyze and solved more than 20 bugs on the website.
- Collaborated and discuss with the UI/UX team, Back End Developer, and more than 10 people to formulate and complete a website mini project

Institut Teknologi Telkom Purwokerto - Indonesia

Sep 2021 - Feb 2022

Database lab assistant

- Teaches database programming, especially SQL and coordinates more than 70 students with the result that all students successfully understand the material with proof of average scores above 80.
- Prepare 10+ materials and modules especially SQL for the current semester and all students can quickly understand the material.
- Evaluated more than 40 practicum reports from students and helped solve problems in database courses faced by students.

Education Level

Institut Teknologi Telkom Purwokerto - Purwokerto, Indonesia

Sep 2020 - Sep 2024 (Expected)

Bachelor Degree in Information System, 3.98/4.00

- Data Structure Project: Simple Application Program Traveling Online.
- · Programming Algorithm Project: FoodCourt Online Simple Application Program.
- · Representing the campus in the ICT Business Development division gemastic competition.

SMA Negeri 9 Bandung - Bandung

Jun 2018 - Jun 2020

High School Diploma in Social Science, 79.18/100.00

• Become a radio announcer on Voice of Nine by providing more than 10 informative and educational information.

Organisational Experience

MP - MBKM - Indonesia

Aug 2022 - Present

Chairman

- Discuss and communicate with more than 500 people from more than 100 different universities in 1 forum.
- Planned and will conduct more than 20 socialization of MBKM programs on campus.
- Sharing with more than 100 students and 5 organizations on campus to advance the MBKM program

HMSI - Purwokerto, Indonesia

Aug 2021 - Jun 2022

Staff at Human Resource Development

- Coordinate 10+ people for MUBES activities and successfully carry out MUBES activities attended by more than 40% of students on campus.
- · Planning Event Webinars with contributions invited more than 200 participants and acted as public relations so that the event ran well.

- Planned, fostered, coordinated, and directed 50+ people for activities related to Campus Anniversary and this event was very well
 organized.
- · Evaluate every event held by the HMSI organization so that the next event will be even better

Skills, Achievements & Other Experience

- Language Skills: Indonesian (Native Proficiency), English (Intermediate).
- **Tech Stack**: C++ (Proficient), SQL (Proficient), HTML (Proficient), CSS (Proficient), Java (Proficient), JavaScript (Intermediate), Python (intermediate), Nuxt Js(Intermediate), Flutter(Intermediate).
- Hard Skills: Programming, Web design, Database Management System, Coding, ITIL Service Design, Digital Marketing, Business Process Management, MicrosoftTool.
- Soft Skills: Adaptive, Critical Thinking, Communication, Collaboration, Leadership.
- Learn to Make Flutter Apps for Beginners from Dicoding (2022): Learn basic layout concepts with widgets and apps that run on mobile & web platforms.
- Learn Basic Web Programming from Dicoding (2022): learn the basic components of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Cloud Practitioner Essentials (Learn AWS Cloud Basics) from Dicoding (2021): Learn about the AWS Cloud and basic global infrastructure, basic principles of AWS Cloud architecture, and basic/core characteristics of deploying and operating in the AWS Cloud.
- The Fundamentals of Digital Marketing from Google Digital Garage (2021): Learn basic SEO concepts, learn responsive web, plan effective and efficient online business strategies, and create engaging marketing campaigns and content.
- **Delegates of Indonesia from International Model United** (2021): Representative of Chile WHO and gave more than 5 arguments about health in Chile.